Guide to the William Rainey Harper Papers 1872-1938
University of Chicago Library
Harper, William Rainey. Papers
1872-1938
12.5 linear feet (18 boxes, 42 volumes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
William Rainey Harper (1856 -1906) was the first president of the University of Chicago, from 1891 to 1906. The collection is comprised primarily of correspondence, and papers not included in the Harper-Judson-Burton section of the Presidents Papers, and is of a somewhat more personal nature that the Presidents Papers. The collection also contains speeches and manuscripts, including Harper's first convocation address; personal correspondence concerning his illness, funeral and memorial services; and clippings, memorials, reprints of articles by Harper and bibliography of his works. It also contains books from the library of William Rainey Harper, including Prophetae Posteriores; notebooks of both Harper and his secretary; and scrapbooks.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Biographical Note
William Rainey Harper (1856 -1906) was the first president of the University of Chicago, from 1891 to 1906. Born on July 24,1856, Harper was the son of Samuel Harper and Ellen Elizabeth Rainey. An excellent student, Harper learned Hebrew at an early age and received his B.A. from Muskingum College at fourteen. After working for a few years in his family's store, in 1873 he went on to graduate work at Yale. There he studied philology, concentrating particularly on Hebrew. His dissertation was entitled, ";A Comparative Study Prepositions in Latin, Greek, Sanskrit and Gothic. Harper earned his Ph.D. in two years, graduating just before his nineteenth birthday.
In 1875, Harper married Ella Paul and they moved to Macon, Tennessee where Harper had found a position as the head of Masonic College. This was the first of several positions, including Denison University, Baptist Union Theological Seminary and Chautauque Institution, he held before returning to Yale in 1886 to teach Hebrew in the Semitic Languages department and the Divinity School.
Harper remained at Yale for only a few years. He had already been a member of the faculty at the Baptist Union Theological Seminary in Morgan Park, Illinois, where he had taught Hebrew. Before leaving, he had been offered the presidency of the failing old University of Chicago, so when the American Baptist Educational Society formed and decided to organize a midwestern Baptist university, Harper was invited to join the organizational committee. With the financial support of John D. Rockefeller, a board of trustees was formed and they soon nominated Harper for the presidency. On February 16, 1891, after lengthy negotiations, he accepted the presidency of the new University of Chicago.
Even before his official acceptance of the presidency, Harper was planning. Although originally envisioned as a Baptist, undergraduate college for the midwest, Harper had bigger ideas. Instead of merely an undergraduate institution Harper wanted to promote his ideal of higher education with a combination of undergraduate teaching and strong support for research. Also part of this plan was a continuation of the kind of correspondence education he had developed at the Baptist Union Theological Seminary and Yale. With this in mind, he began an intensive period of recruitment and building. Harper worked tirelessly to recruit first class faculty and raise money for his institution. He brought in faculty from a range of fields and institutions, using his persuasive skills and tenacity, as well as promises of time for research, to convince them to join the new university.
Eventually, the university came to include graduate degree programs, adult education programs, athletics, a university press and extension services. These were in addition to the undergraduate college. It was formed according to the plan of two years of general study of the classics followed by two years of greater specialization. Harper himself taught in the Department of Semitic Languages and Literatures. Despite the burden of administrative activities, Harper was the chair of his department as well as president, he felt it was important to teach. Even with this interest in teaching, a key part of Harper's vision of higher education was research and scholarship. Harper wanted his senior faculty to have ample time and freedom to pursue their research interests as well as teach. This emphasis on research was somewhat novel at the time, but Harper was able to exploit the absence of traditional constraints in forming a new university in order to give research and scholarship a central role.
When he was not occupied with his educational plan, Harper was raising money and soliciting donations, especially from John D. Rockefeller. In addition to the recruitment of faculty and the organization of programs of study, there were buildings to be built and academic ceremonies to be held. During all this activity Harper continued to write, producing biblical commentaries and other works, and maintaining a passionate interest in sports. He never stopped planning for the future and continued to expand the university and include new programs and schools over the following years. This caused problems in budgeting, however, and Harper ran up large deficits in his fifteen years in the presidency. These financial problems would not be addressed until Harry Pratt Judson was appointed president after Harper.
In 1905, Harper became ill. Although he continued to work and teach throughout the period of his illness, Harper died on January 10, 1906. He left behind the foundations of the University of Chicago, which would continue to grow and change after his death, but never lose his emphasis on a combination of undergraduate education and scholarly research.
Harper and his wife, Ella, had three sons, Samuel Northrup, Paul and Donald, and one daughter, Davida.
Scope Note
The William Rainey Harper papers is comprised primarily of correspondence, and papers not included in the Harper-Judson-Burton section of the Presidents Papers, and is of a somewhat more personal nature than the Presidents Papers. This collection has been arranged into six series: Correspondence, Speeches and Manuscripts, Personal, Writings, Books from the Library of William Rainey Harper and Notebooks and Scrapbooks.
The first series, Correspondence, has eight subseries. Divisions of material among these subseries is not strict. The first subseries, General, contains correspondence with a variety of correspondents including University of Chicago faculty such as Ernest DeWitt Burton and Albion Small and other university faculty and presidents. It also contains some correspondence with family members. This subseries is arranged chronologically and the names of the correspondents in each folder have been listed alphabetically. Most of the letters in subseries 1, General, have been individually described. These descriptions are located in the second volume (paper copy only) to the William Rainey Harper Papers. The second subseries is Distinguished Persons. It contains a certain quantity of correspondence that has been separated from the General correspondence and includes correspondence with F. T. Gates, Harry Pratt Judson and others. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent. The third subseries, Family, contains some of Harper's correspondence with his family and other personal correspondence. Subseries 5, Academic, contains correspondence with students including corrected lessons of Rev. Daniel Seymour. The sixth subseries, Founding of the University of Chicago, has correspondence about the founding of the university, correspondence concerning Harper's selection for the presidency and similar information. Related to this is subseries seven, Early appointments, that contains correspondence regarding early appointments to the faculty. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject. The last subseries, Harper-Shepardson Business, consists of two bound volumes of correspondence between Harper and his secretary, Shepardson.
Series II, Speeches and Manuscripts, includes Harper's first convocation address, his Quarterly Statement, Spring 1896 and lecture notes.
Series III, Personal, contains material related to Harper's illness and death. It includes correspondence with Harper's doctors and concerning his last operation. Also, Series III includes material about Harper's funeral and memorial services and letters of sympathy sent to Ella Harper, Samuel Harper and to University officials. These three correspondents determine the three groups that the letters are divided into and the three groups are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Additionally there are tributes, memorials, clippings and correspondence and notes concerning Harper's desk.
The fourth series, Writings, contains a few reprints of articles by Harper and a bibliography of Harper's works, as well as a few reviews of his works. The articles are arranged chronologically.
Series V, Books from the Library of William Rainey Harper, includes three small volumes, one of which, Prophetae Posteriores, is heavily annotated.
Series VI, Notebooks and Scrapbooks, has three main divisions. The first group is the ";Red Books”, which are arranged chronologically. Second are the Miscellaneous Notebooks, also arranged chronologically, although three of these are undated. The last group, Harper's Secretary's notebooks, appear to be notebooks kept by his secretary. They are also arranged chronologically and include a volume entitled ";General Reference Book”.
Browse finding aids by topic.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Harper, William Rainey, 1856-1906; Gates, Frederick Taylor, 1853-1929; Goodspeed, Thomas Wakefield, 1842-1927; Judson, Harry Pratt, 1849-1927; Shepardson, Francis Wayland, 1862-1937; University of Chicago -- Administration.University of Chicago -- History; University of Chicago -- Presidents
INVENTORY
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Correspondence, Letters to Children, July 1889 - December 1905, Carroll, Willie Foresman, Elizabeth Goodpeeed Harper, Davida Harper, Paul Vincent Harper, Samuel N. Johnson, Margaret Lorimer, George Hoarce Lowden, Florence Mathews, Nora McKee, Howard Harper Pierce, Caroline (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Undated Letters, Benet-Maury Burgess, I.B. Clapp, Edward B. Coolidge, Dr. Crosby, D.C. Crowe, Martha Foote Faris, Elizabeth Fiero, A. Conro Lawrence, Margaret Woods McLaren, Alex Niel, Harriet Penrose, Mary L. Reed, Elizabeth A. Robertson, Alice D. Robertson, George Eustis Robinson, Williard H. Senn, NicholasSprague, Mrs. A.A. Sprague, Lucia E. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Undated Letters, Abbot, Lyman Beckley, J.F. Bitting, W.C. Bond, Mrs. Joseph Browne, F.F. Burnham, Mrs. E.R. Buttrick, Wallace H. Butterworth, Benjamin Cole, George E. Dingee, Gertrude P. Farwell, J.V. Farwell, Mrs. J.V. Faunce, W.H.P. Hefferan, Mrs. W.S. List of Committee members of NEA on Paris Exposition Mathews, Shailers Moore, Addison Webster Russell, Howard H. Starr, Ellen G. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, May 8, 1883 -- January 7, 1888, Beecher, Willis J. Board of Trustees of the University of Chicago Broadus, John A. Charles Scribner's Sons Clark, John C.C. Douglas, B. Goodspeed. T.W. Griffen, LaRoy F. Haupt, Paul Jastrow, Morris Lee, [H.?] McKee, W.P. Members of Hebrew Summer School (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, January 13, -- September 28, 1888, Bitting, W.C. Beckley, J. T. Briggs, C.A. Burgess, I.B. Clissold, H. R. Committee on Resolution of the P.E. Divinity School Ivison, Blakeman, andCo. Jacob, B.F. MacArthur, R. S. McKee, W.P. Nordell, P. A. Resolution of the Special Committee on Revision (Confidential Copy) Scribner's Vincent, Bishop John H. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, October 9, - November 26, 1888, Burgess, Issac B. Charles Scribner's Sons D. Appleton and Co. Ivison, Blakeman and Company Jastrow, Morris McKee, W.P. Mogyorosi, A.J. Olson, Edward Simpson, B. Taylor, J.M. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, November 26, - December 24, 1888, Burgess, I.B. Burnham, S. Haupt, Paul McKee, W.P. Schwartz, J. Scribner's Stevens, William Arnold Taylor, J.M. The Committee (Francis Brown, W.R. Harper, Charles Rufus Brown) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, December 28, 1888 - February 18, 1889, Blackhall, C.R. (of Amer. Bap. Publ.) Green, Wm. Henry McKee, W.P. Morse, Richard Nordell, Philip (Pastor First Baptist Church) Weston, Henry G. Unidentified (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, February 21, - April 29, 1889, Beckley, John T. Burgess, Isacc B. Elder, J. F. Mannatt, Irving J. Pepper, Wm. Sampey, John R. Strong, A. H. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, May 4, - November 4, 1889, Abbott, Lyman Briggs, C.A. Broadhurst, W.A. Burgess, Isacc B. Craig, S.A. Davidson, Samuel Faunce, W. H. P. Goodsell, S. F. Green, W. Henry Johnson, E.H. Pepper, Wm. Stifler, J.M. Vincent, Bishop John H. Vincent, George E. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, May 4, - November 4, 1889, White, Hamilton (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, November 22, 1889 - March 15, 1890, Abbott, Lyman Bridgman, H.A. Brown Burnham, S. Calvert, J. B. Dawson, E.B. Green, W. Henry Griffith, B. Jefferson, Charles E. Lee, Samuel H. MacArthur, R.S. McKee, W.P. Nordell, Philp Olson, S.E. Parkhurst, Charles Reichelt, John A. Stuart, Lewis Trumbull, H. Clay Tucker, Wm. J. Whiting, Sarah F. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, March 21, - June 4, 1889, American Institute of Sacred Literature, report from Anderson, Asher Bitting. W.C. Burgess, Issac B. Butrick, Wallace Cowles, Louise F. Green, W. Henry Jacobs, B.F. Muller, Max Payne, John W. Perkins, Rev. Sydney K.B. Pruott, J. Sayce, A.H. Sayce, A.H. Trumbull, H. Clay Williams, Leighton (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, June 5, - August 21, 1889, American Book Company Brown, F. Burgess, I.B. Clarke, H.M. Dana, James Dwight, Timothy Fagg. M. Rose, Howard B. Henderson, C.R. Johnson, E.H. Lee, Samuel H. McKee, W.P. Sanders, Frank K. Seymour, T.D. Vincent, John H. Woods, H.C. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, August 27, - November 1, 1889, Austin, Ben W. Beckley, J.T. Bixby, M.H. Burgess, I.B. Coman, Katherine Gordon, John Hartshorned, W.N. Jones, Nelson B. Lee, Samuel H. McKee, W.P. Thayer, Lucius H. Vincent, John H. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, November 13, - December 30, 1890, Bridgman, H.A. Burgess, I.B. Calvert, J.B. D'Ooge, M.L. Gordon, Elizabeth P. Green, W.H. Haupt, Paul Hovey, Geo. Rice Johnson, M.F. Lee, Samuel L. Moss, Lemuel Robinson, E. J. Rogers, Robert W. Sharpe, John C. Squires, Jas. Duane (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, January 4, - January 23, 1891, Abbott, Lyman Beal, M.B. and E. Flagg Voorhies Beckley, John T. Commercial Club, Secretary of Faunce, W.H.P. Huling, Ray Green Miles, J.J. Nichols, W.H. Nordell, Philip A. Northrup, G.W. Sharpe, John C. Smith, Willard A. Vincent, John H. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, January 25 - March 21, 1889, Bitting, W.C. Brown, Charles Rufus Buck, Carl D. Davies, Rev. Gethin Eaton, T.T. Faunce, W.H.P. Felsenthal, Eli. B. Fernald, J.C. Hume, John Hutchins, Herbert B. Johnson, E.H. King, J. M. Lewis, Denslow Lyon, D.G. Ogden, Robert C. Sampey, John R. Scribner's Stuart, Lewis Young, C.E. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, March 21, - June 19, 1891, Abbott, Lyman Braodus, John A. Davies, Rev. Gethin Dewey, Melvil Eaton, T.T. Green, W. H. Griffith, B. Head, Franklin H. The Homiletic Review Hovey, Alvah Humpstone, John Illinois Music Teacher's Association Judson, H. P. Kaye, Jas. R. Lyon, D.G. Mott, J.R. Ober, C.K. Paton, Lewis B. Sampey, J.R. Sanders, Frank K. Schwetzky, Otto Sherwood, Sidney Trumbull, H. Clay (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, June 20 - October 27, 1891, Anderson, Mary D. Baer, J.W. Braishin, Edward Burgess, I.B. Butterworth, Benjamin Clark, Francois E. Coates, A.S. Davis, G.W. Griffith, B. Hilprecht, H.B. Judson, H. P. Lewis, Cora E. Macalpine, Geo. D. McLaren, Alex Parsons, W.M. Sayce, A.H. Smith, Willard A. Strong, Augustus H. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, October 27 - December 26, 1891, Baer, J.W. Chapman, John H. Eliot, Charles W. Gilman, D.C. Griffith, B.W. Judson, H. P. McCormick, Cyrus H. McKee, W.P. Peabody, Henry W. Peck, Ferd W. Rowland, A.I. Scott, James W. Smith, J.A. Trumbull, H. Clay Tustin, J (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, January 1 - February 8, 1892, Andrews, Benjamin Barrows, Walter M. Gilman Larned, M.D. Lindsay, Saml. I. Marshall, J.T. McKee, W.P. Merrill, Geo. R. Moore, M. Parker, F.S. Roberts, R.D. Rowland, A.I. Rubinkam, N.I. Smith, Willard A. Vaile, E.O. Wachsmann, Dr. Siegfried Walker, P.R. Woodward, W. Redin (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, February 9 - April 22, 1892, Barbour, H.H. Bonney, Charles C. Burgess, I.B. Burrill, D.J. Carus, Paul Chaney, N.H. Colby, Charles L. Cook, E.H. Craig, Jas. A. Dingee, Gertrude P. Dougherty, N.C. Errant, Joseph W. Evans, S.G. Fell Griffin, Edward H. Luzac and Co. Marshall, J.T. Marvin, Arthur Mason, O. T. Nordell, P. Odell, D.D. Rogers, George D. Stakely, Chas. A. Tyler, Moses Coit Wells, Amos R. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, April 30 - August 19, 1892, Binkerd, O.W. Bitting, W.C. Bronson, Frank M. Carroll, H.K. Cobb, S.B. Crandall, L.A. Harrowes, Henry D. Holton, Edward Paxton Jackson, Jas. L. Jones, Nelson B. Kunz, August Lane, Supt. Merriam, E.F. Murch, C. Northrop, Stephen Abbott Perry, Geo. A. Phillips, A.M. Shaler, N.S. Starrett, Helen E. Washburn, Mrs. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, August 27 - December 17, 1892, Boas, Franz Bowersox, J.B. Broadhurst, W.A. Cunningham, Fannie L. First Assistant Postmaster General Fison, Sherwood George, Moshie Gilbert, George H. Hobbs, C.A. Laughlin, J. Laurence Randolph, Isham Reed, Josephine Reynolds, James B. Stewart, John A. Williams, Norman (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, January 2, - June 8, 1893, Alden, L. Beulah Bollard, W. Burr, Hoarce L. Feibleman, Isidore Feldman, W.H. Ford, J.W. Gilman, Pres. Herdman, T.H. Job, Samuel Kloetz, Rev. W. Leavitt, Edgar Mooney, James Reynolds, James B. Scribner's Sprague, Joseph W. Traver, H.R. Wilson, Mrs. A.K. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, June 12, - November 15, 1893, Adams, Deo. E. Boardman, George Dana Delano Forbes, S.A. Hastings, James Hathaway, Frank R. Johnson, Franklin McKee, W.P. O'Rorkey, Maurice G. Payne Rogers, Dr. L.D. Standard Oil Co. Wallace, James Weber, W.L. Winship, A.E. Young, C.Y. Unidenified (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, December 1893, Eaton, T.T. Prestridge, John N. Walkansky, Pierce (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, January 6 - March 9, 1894, Allen, Ira W. Beale, F.B. Bitting, W.C. Broadhurst, W.A. Burnham, S. Canfield, James H. Colwell, R.S. Eastman, Geroge Getchell, Edwin F. Gray, W.C. Harmon, A.E. Johnson, L.A. Johnson, P.M. Wachmann, Dr. Welling, James C. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, March 20 - June 16, 1894, Bacon, B.W. Burton, E.D. Draper, A.S. Easley, R.M. Fercken, D.D. French, W.M.R. Hewlett, Mrs. E Horswell, Charles Keen, W.W. Record, J.F. Ridpath, Clark Edward Rockefeller, Laura C. Scibner's Seymour, J.D. Shepardson Jr., Daniel Thomas, W.I. Thwing, Pres. Charles F. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, June 21, - September 22, 1894, Brooks, George G. Burnham, S. Burton, E.D. Dana, Charles A. Eversole, Henry Fowler, Mr. Green, And. H. Hastings, James Johnson, E.H. Moulton, Prof. Pennell, W.H. Reynolds, Myra Snow, President Sproull, Prof. Vincent, George E. Ward, William H. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, September 22, - November 23, 1894, Barrows, John Henry Brown, Charles Rufus Davies, F.B. Denis, F.B. E[?], Helen Paul, Rev. David Gentles, H.W. Hastings, James Jackson, John L. Potts, William Robertson, Geo. E. Rogers, P.S. Sanders, Frank The Honorable Secretary of the Victoria Institute Wayland, H.L. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, November 24, 1894 - December 31, 1894, Bacon, Benjamin W. Burton, E. D. Danziger, Rabbi D.A. Walker, Clyde B. Hackett, Dr. Sarah Hill, Mr. Kingsbury, J.T. Middleditch, R.H. Moore, J.H. Reese, Rev. Chas. A. Williams, W.A. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1894 Addenda, Barrows, John Henry Good, M.B. Knapp, Laughlin, Whitman, Michelson, Hale, von Holst, and Anderson Palmer, Alice Freeman (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, January 3, - March 6, 1895, Barrows, Rev. John Henry Butler, Nicholas Murray Campbell, W.H. Capps Cobb, Mr. Crane, Cornelia Dickerson, J.S. Eastman, Fred W. Foster, Prof. G.B. Georges, Mooshie Gifford, E.P. (missing) Herrick, Robert Hill, Mr. Jensen, A.F.F. Johnson, Dr. Klingler, Rev. Paul G. Piddock, Rev. Chas. A. Risley, Edwin H. Rockefeller: J.D. Ryerson, Martin A. Shepardson, Daniel Small, Dr. Whitehead, Louis G. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, March 6, - March 28, 1895, Angell, James B. Berle, A.A. Bissell, A.P. Bonney, Charles, C. Burnham, S. Chalmers, James Eastman, G. W. French, W. M. R. Fulcomer, Daniel Goodwin, A.W. Guliver, Miss Julia H. Hargrave, H.L. Hulley, Professor Lincoln Hutchinson, C.L. Ingals, Dr. E. Fletcher Judson, H. P. Mace, W. H. Matz, Miss Mary L. Parker, A.K. Peck, Ferd. W. Salisbury, Prof. Springfield, J.W. Thwing, Pres. Von Holst, Prof. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, April 1, - April 30, 1895, Barrows, John Henry Beaman, J.F. Burnham, S. Chalmers, William E. Crawford, Pres. Dewey, Melvill Donaldson, Henry H. Elsdon, J.G. Goodspeed, Dr. Gore, Rev. Charles Hoyt, John W. Hussey, G.B. Lamson, L.J. Mace, W.H. Pierce, John O. Shepardson, Daniel Thompson, Rev. C.F. Weston, Frank E. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, April 30, -- May 10, 1895, Briggs, C.A. Brown, C.R. Butts, Miss Carney, J.P. Curtis, Prof. E.L. Cutting Faunce, Rev. W.H.P. French, W.M.R. Fulcomer, Daniel Gates, Mr. Gerhart, C.S. Goodwin, W.W. Jones, Mr. Mrs. Haskell Otis, H.H. Roby, Mrs. Smith, George Adam Stagg Stalker, Rev. James Zenos, Prof. A.O. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, May 10, - May 31, 1895, Bingham, Dr. John Chalmers, James Chamberlain, Prof. Dowd, Mrs. Elizabeth DuBlois, Pres. A.K. Gunsaulus, Jensen, Clara, M. Jones, Rev. Jenkin Lloyd Kohlsaat, Judge Mittchell, Prof. S.C. Palmer, Mrs. Peck, Ferd W. Rand, John C. Richey, W.E. Rubinkam, Rev. Nathaniel Sharpless, Pres. Issac Stratton, Prof. Vincent, Rev. John H. White, Mrs. Hugh A. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, June 1, - June 25, 1895, Barnard, E.E. Barnes, Clifford Barrows, John Henry Buck, CD Buzzell, E.A. Dewey, Melvil Faunce, W.H.P. Gunderson, Henrik Hale Haynes, Rev. Myron W. Hendrickson, Prof. Geo. L. Hirsch, Emil G. Johnson, Dr. Kelly, Mrs. McLeish Pierce, R.W. Price, Prof. Smith, M.W. Wilmarth, Mres. Mary H. Foster, Pres. Charles (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, June 25, - June 26, 1895, Garnett, Miss Fanne Storey, Ralph E. Kent, Charles Foster (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, July 15 - August 23, 1895, Anderson, Mrs. Bemis, Prof. Burton, E. D. Creve Coeur Club, Sec. of Cutting, Mr. Davies, D.E. Dewey, John Eakin, C.L. Edwards, Rev. Arthur T. Fairbairn, Mr. Fellows, W.T. French, Mrs. F.H. Handy, S. Speiden Pietzsh, Dr. Smith, Rev. F.M. Steed, Carl W. Stuart, Lewis Tanner, John S. Van Osdel, Mr. Walker, Geo. C. Young, Dr. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, August 26 - September 23, 1895, Barnard, E.F. Butler, Prof. Corthell, Mr. Dewey, Prof. John Dickerson, J.S. Dixson, Mrs. Funk, Mr. I.K. Grant, John C. Hale, W.E. Harris, Pres. Haynes, Rev. Myron W. Hulley, Lincoln Jones, Mr. Kohlsaat, Mr. Mac Cracken, Chancellor Swan, J.N. Taylor, President (Box 2, Folder 17)